Donald and Charlotte MacJannet Papers MS024
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Personal papers, 1824 -- 1999; 1916 -- 1986; MS024.001; 27.9 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes; 2 Digital Object(s)
  - [Coat of arms and documentation], 1892 -- 1940; MS024.001.240.00004 (Box Shared 132)
    Coat of arms feature a cross moline argent sable, a ducal coronet, and a war horse passant with trappings over the motto "semper paratus" and "Upton". Documentation from the International Heraldic Institute, Ltd. in Washington, D.C.
  - [Original illustrated poster for the MacJannet School of Sun Valley], 1940 -- 1943; MS024.001.240.00005; Barsis, Max (Box Shared 132)
  - [Drawing of a building], 1933; MS024.001.240.00006 (Box Shared 132)
    Pencil. Signed A. M. (?) Sutherland.
  - [Document commemorating the confirmation of Charlotte Blensdorf], 1917-03-04; MS024.001.240.00007 (Box Shared 132)
  - The happy prince, 1954; MS024.001.240.00008 (Box Shared 132)
    Contains clippings from a magazine or newspaper spread with photographs from Prince Philip Duke of Edinburgh's schooldays, aged six to nine, at the MacJannet American School at St. Cloud, on the outskirts of Paris. The clippings are glued to a piece of cardboard.
- Camp records and correspondence, 1924 -- 1996; 1930 -- 1960; MS024.002; 11.3 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials relating to the camp at Talloires including camp applications, correspondence about camp with campers, parents, suppliers and others. This material includes the aid to orphans (Entre'Aide) information from after WWII that often describes France and the French situation after the war. Also includes personal correspondence with former campers and counselors.
  The MacJannet Camps on the shores of Lake Annecy, Haute Savoie, France, founded in 1924, were a delightful summer playground for children of all nationalities until the outbreak of war in 1939. During World War II the camp was lent to the American Friends Service Committee and was a refuge for war orphans. The camps reopened in 1946 and sessions were held every summer until the property was sold to Gillette in 1968.
  This series is not arranged.
  This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Camp, 1951; MS024.002.165.00001 (Box 165)
  - A voir pour, 1953; MS024.002.165.00002 (Box 165)
    To Sea for 1953
  - Applications - counselors, 1952; MS024.002.165.00003 (Box 165)
  - Applications - counselors, 1952; MS024.002.165.00004 (Box 165)
  - Application - Jr. counselors, 1951; MS024.002.165.00005 (Box 165)
  - Bossert, letters, 1950 -- 1951; MS024.002.165.00006 (Box 165)
  - Camp/camper publications, 1946 -- 1958; MS024.002.165.00007 (Box 165)
  - Camp activities/Aid to French children, 1949 -- 1950; MS024.002.165.00008 (Box 165)
  - Camp correspondence, 1950; MS024.002.165.00009 (Box 165)
  - Campers, 1949; MS024.002.165.00010 (Box 165)
  - Campers, 1949; MS024.002.165.00011 (Box 165)
  - Campers, 1949; MS024.002.165.00012 (Box 165)
  - Campers, 1959; MS024.002.165.00013 (Box 165)
  - Campers, 1959; MS024.002.165.00014 (Box 165)
  - Campers, letters, 1985; MS024.002.165.00015 (Box 165)
  - Camper informations, 1946; MS024.002.165.00016 (Box 165)
  - Camper informations, 1950; MS024.002.165.00017 (Box 165)
  - Camper lists, 1948 -- 1955; MS024.002.165.00018 (Box 165)
  - Campers who have left camp, 1939; MS024.002.165.00019 (Box 165)
  - Campers who have left camp, 1939; MS024.002.165.00020 (Box 165)
  - Cont. supplies, 1946; MS024.002.165.00021 (Box 165)
  - Copies of letters, 1949; MS024.002.165.00022 (Box 165)
  - Copies of letters, 1949; MS024.002.165.00023 (Box 165)
  - Counselors, 1946; MS024.002.165.00024 (Box 165)
  - Counselors, 1946; MS024.002.165.00025 (Box 165)
  - French campers, 1949; MS024.002.165.00026 (Box 165)
  - French counselors in America, 1946; MS024.002.165.00027 (Box 165)
  - French American counselors, 1949; MS024.002.165.00028 (Box 165)
  - Former campers, letters, clippings and articles, 1949; MS024.002.165.00029 (Box 165)
  - Letters, 1955; MS024.002.165.00030 (Box 165)
  - Letters, 1955; MS024.002.165.00031 (Box 165)
  - Letters re: camp, 1950; MS024.002.165.00032 (Box 165)
  - Lists, 1946; MS024.002.165.00033 (Box 165)
  - MacJannet trophies, 1925 -- 1928; MS024.002.165.00034 (Box 165)
  - Letters, 1949; MS024.002.165.00035 (Box 165)
  - Loose letters, 1949; MS024.002.165.00036 (Box 165)
  - MacJannet committee for aid to French children papers, 1946; MS024.002.165.00037 (Box 165)
  - Men counselors, 1949; MS024.002.165.00038 (Box 165)
  - Official camp papers, 1947 -- 1955; MS024.002.165.00039 (Box 165)
  - 'Pending', 1951; MS024.002.165.00040 (Box 165)
  - 'Pending' camp material, 1946; MS024.002.165.00041 (Box 165)
  - Reports and financial statements, 1946; MS024.002.165.00042 (Box 165)
  - Reunion plans and regional meetings, 1974; MS024.002.165.00043 (Box 165)
  - Shipping and supplies, 1946; MS024.002.165.00044 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1949; MS024.002.165.00045 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1949; MS024.002.165.00046 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1949; MS024.002.165.00047 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1949; MS024.002.165.00048 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1950; MS024.002.165.00049 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1950; MS024.002.165.00050 (Box 165)
  - Staff, 1950; MS024.002.165.00051 (Box 165)
  - Swimming, 1937; MS024.002.165.00052 (Box 165)
  - Women counselors, 1949; MS024.002.165.00053 (Box 165)
  - Adresses a choisir, 1947; MS024.002.166.00001 (Box 166)
  - Addresses, master list, 1946 -- 1968; MS024.002.166.00002 (Box 166)
  - American relief for France, 1946; MS024.002.166.00003 (Box 166)
  - Camp - camper publications, 1928 -- 1964; MS024.002.166.00004 (Box 166)
  - Camp publications, 1936 -- 1948; MS024.002.166.00005 (Box 166)
  - Camp publicity, 1949 -- 1955; MS024.002.166.00006 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1955; MS024.002.166.00007 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1955; MS024.002.166.00008 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1955; MS024.002.166.00009 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1957; MS024.002.166.00010 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1957; MS024.002.166.00011 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1957; MS024.002.166.00012 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1958; MS024.002.166.00013 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1958; MS024.002.166.00014 (Box 166)
  - Campers, 1958; MS024.002.166.00015 (Box 166)
  - Challet chatterer, 1938; MS024.002.166.00016 (Box 166)
  - Challet chatterer, 1939; MS024.002.166.00017 (Box 166)
  - Cont-money, letters re orphan camp, 1946 -- 1949; MS024.002.166.00018 (Box 166)
  - Cont-money, letters re orphan camp, 1946 -- 1949; MS024.002.166.00019 (Box 166)
  - Counselors, 1958; MS024.002.166.00020 (Box 166)
  - Counselors, 1959; MS024.002.166.00021 (Box 166)
  - Counselors, 1963 -- 1970; MS024.002.166.00022 (Box 166)
  - Letters, 1949; MS024.002.166.00023 (Box 166)
  - Letters, 1949; MS024.002.166.00024 (Box 166)
  - Letters, 1949; MS024.002.166.00025 (Box 166)
  - Loose camp material(includes history), 1970; MS024.002.166.00026 (Box 166)
  - Loose material, letters, 1982; MS024.002.166.00027 (Box 166)
  - Newsclippings on camp, 1948 -- 1968; MS024.002.166.00028 (Box 166)
  - Pan-American society, 1945 -- 1949; MS024.002.166.00029 (Box 166)
  - Pan-American society, 1945 -- 1949; MS024.002.166.00030 (Box 166)
  - American counselors, 1946; MS024.002.172.00001 (Box 172)
  - American teams, 1950; MS024.002.172.00002 (Box 172)
  - Applications, campers, 1950; MS024.002.172.00003 (Box 172)
  - Camp, 1950 -- 1951; MS024.002.172.00004 (Box 172)
  - Campers, 1946 -- 1947; MS024.002.172.00005 (Box 172)
  - Campers, 1950; MS024.002.172.00006 (Box 172)
  - Campers, 1950; MS024.002.172.00007 (Box 172)
  - Campers, 1951; MS024.002.172.00008 (Box 172)
  - Campers, 1956; MS024.002.172.00009 (Box 172)
  - Campers' correspondence, 1950; MS024.002.172.00010 (Box 172)
  - Campers' correspondence, 1950; MS024.002.172.00011 (Box 172)
  - Campers' correspondence, 1950; MS024.002.172.00012 (Box 172)
  - Campers' correspondence, 1950; MS024.002.172.00013 (Box 172)
  - Campers and counselors not coming, 1951; MS024.002.172.00014 (Box 172)
  - Cont. Movey, 1948 -- 1949; MS024.002.172.00015 (Box 172)
  - Contributers, pros., 1946; MS024.002.172.00016 (Box 172)
  - Contributers, pros., 1946; MS024.002.172.00017 (Box 172)
  - Contributers, pros., 1946; MS024.002.172.00018 (Box 172)
  - Contributors, supplies Prospective contributors, 1946 -- 1949; MS024.002.172.00019 (Box 172)
  - Contributors, supplies, 1950; MS024.002.172.00020 (Box 172)
  - Counselors not coming, 1950; MS024.002.172.00021 (Box 172)
  - Counselors, 1951; MS024.002.172.00022 (Box 172)
  - Counselors, 1951; MS024.002.172.00023 (Box 172)
  - Counselors, 1951; MS024.002.172.00024 (Box 172)
  - French camps, 1949; MS024.002.172.00025 (Box 172)
  - French counselors, 1948; MS024.002.172.00026 (Box 172)
  - French counselors, 1950; MS024.002.172.00027 (Box 172)
  - Invitations fete, 1950; MS024.002.172.00028 (Box 172)
  - Jr. counselors and camper applications, 1952 -- 1954; MS024.002.172.00029 (Box 172)
  - Jr. counselors and camper applications, 1952 -- 1954; MS024.002.172.00030 (Box 172)
  - Jr. counselors, 1952 -- 1954; MS024.002.172.00031 (Box 172)
  - MacJannet committee, letters, 1946; MS024.002.172.00032 (Box 172)
  - MacJannet committee for aid to French children, 1948; MS024.002.172.00033 (Box 172)
  - MacJannet committee for aid to French children, 1949; MS024.002.172.00034 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1946; MS024.002.172.00035 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1946; MS024.002.172.00036 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1946; MS024.002.172.00037 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1946; MS024.002.172.00038 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1946; MS024.002.172.00039 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1948; MS024.002.172.00040 (Box 172)
  - Staff, 1948; MS024.002.172.00041 (Box 172)
  - Application, 1949; MS024.002.173.00001 (Box 173)
  - Applications - counselors, 1954; MS024.002.173.00002 (Box 173)
  - Applications for enrollment, 1952 -- 1959; MS024.002.173.00003 (Box 173)
  - Camp, 1939; MS024.002.173.00004 (Box 173)
  - Camp 1936 Challet Chatterer, MS024.002.173.00005 (Box 173)
  - Camp Applicants, 1956; MS024.002.173.00006 (Box 173)
  - Camp Counselors, 1956; MS024.002.173.00007 (Box 173)
  - Camp, 1958; MS024.002.173.00008 (Box 173)
  - Camp newspaper, 1938; MS024.002.173.00009 (Box 173)
  - Camp newspapers, 1937; MS024.002.173.00010 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1952; MS024.002.173.00011 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1956; MS024.002.173.00012 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1956; MS024.002.173.00013 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1956; MS024.002.173.00014 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1960; MS024.002.173.00015 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1960; MS024.002.173.00016 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1960; MS024.002.173.00017 (Box 173)
  - Campers, 1961; MS024.002.173.00018 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1954; MS024.002.173.00019 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1954; MS024.002.173.00020 (Box 173)
  - Counselors [campers], 1955; MS024.002.173.00021 (Box 173)
  - Counselors and campers, 1955; MS024.002.173.00022 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1956; MS024.002.173.00023 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1960; MS024.002.173.00024 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1961; MS024.002.173.00025 (Box 173)
  - Counselors, 1961; MS024.002.173.00026 (Box 173)
  - Counselors pending, 1963; MS024.002.173.00027 (Box 173)
  - Hikes, Herbert, 1937; MS024.002.173.00028 (Box 173)
  - Loose letters, 1936; MS024.002.173.00029 (Box 173)
  - Schedules, 1953; MS024.002.173.00030 (Box 173)
  - Applicants, 1947; MS024.002.174.00001 (Box 174)
  - Applicants, 1947; MS024.002.174.00002 (Box 174)
  - Applicants, 1948; MS024.002.174.00003 (Box 174)
  - Camp business, 1936 -- 1937; MS024.002.174.00004 (Box 174)
  - Camp employee applications, 1955; MS024.002.174.00005 (Box 174)
  - Camp, lists and letters, 1946 -- 1949; MS024.002.174.00006 (Box 174)
  - Camp organization, 1947; MS024.002.174.00007 (Box 174)
  - Camp organization, 1958; MS024.002.174.00008 (Box 174)
  - Campers, 1951; MS024.002.174.00009 (Box 174)
  - [Campers and counselors], 1951; MS024.002.174.00010 (Box 174)
  - Campers who have camp, A-C, 1939; MS024.002.174.00011 (Box 174)
  - Campers who have camp, C-G, 1939; MS024.002.174.00012 (Box 174)
  - Campers who have camp, H-L, 1939; MS024.002.174.00013 (Box 174)
  - Chemin de Fer, 1950; MS024.002.174.00014 (Box 174)
  - Copies of letters, 1938; MS024.002.174.00015 (Box 174)
  - Copies of letters to sponsors, 1949; MS024.002.174.00016 (Box 174)
  - Counselors [Applications and rejections], 1948; MS024.002.174.00017 (Box 174)
  - Counselors, 1949; MS024.002.174.00018 (Box 174)
  - Daily schedules, 1950; MS024.002.174.00019 (Box 174)
  - Departs campeurs, 1946; MS024.002.174.00020 (Box 174)
  - Letters, 1950; MS024.002.174.00021 (Box 174)
  - Letters of application, 1950; MS024.002.174.00022 (Box 174)
  - Letters to counselors, 1948; MS024.002.174.00023 (Box 174)
  - Lists, 1950; MS024.002.174.00024 (Box 174)
  - Loose letters, 1936; MS024.002.174.00025 (Box 174)
  - Loose letters, 1945 -- 1946; MS024.002.174.00026 (Box 174)
  - Loose letters, 1948; MS024.002.174.00027 (Box 174)
  - Loose letters, 1949 -- 1951; MS024.002.174.00028 (Box 174)
  - MacJannet notes, 1952; MS024.002.174.00029 (Box 174)
  - Moniteurs acceptes,1959, MS024.002.174.00030 (Box 174)
  - Newsletters, 1955; MS024.002.174.00031 (Box 174)
  - Prospective campers and students, 1946; MS024.002.174.00032 (Box 174)
  - Publicity, 1946 -- 1950; MS024.002.174.00033 (Box 174)
  - Publicity, 1951; MS024.002.174.00034 (Box 174)
  - Rich-Jack, 1951; MS024.002.174.00035 (Box 174)
  - Schedules - individual counselors - Herbert, 1937; MS024.002.174.00036 (Box 174)
  - Scrapbook, campers drawlings, 35th season, MS024.002.174.00037 (Box 174)
  - Sponsors, 1947 -- 1949; MS024.002.174.00038 (Box 174)
  - Songs of the MacJannet camp, 1950; MS024.002.174.00039 (Box 174)
  - Staff, 1947; MS024.002.174.00040 (Box 174)
  - Staff, 1947; MS024.002.174.00041 (Box 174)
  - Staff, 1947; MS024.002.174.00042 (Box 174)
  - Staff and counselors, 1951; MS024.002.174.00043 (Box 174)
  - Talloires counselors, 1947; MS024.002.174.00044 (Box 174)
  - Youth Argosy, 1950; MS024.002.174.00045 (Box 174)
  - Biographies, boys, 1950; MS024.002.175.00001 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1950; MS024.002.175.00002 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1950 -- 1955; MS024.002.175.00003 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1954; MS024.002.175.00004 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1954; MS024.002.175.00005 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1954; MS024.002.175.00006 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1957; MS024.002.175.00007 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1961; MS024.002.175.00008 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1961; MS024.002.175.00009 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1962; MS024.002.175.00010 (Box 175)
  - Campers, 1962; MS024.002.175.00011 (Box 175)
  - Correspondence with former counselors, 1952; MS024.002.175.00012 (Box 175)
  - Counselors, 1950; MS024.002.175.00013 (Box 175)
  - Counselors, 1957; MS024.002.175.00014 (Box 175)
  - Counselors (and campers), 1957; MS024.002.175.00015 (Box 175)
  - Couselors, 1961; MS024.002.175.00016 (Box 175)
  - Counselors, 1962; MS024.002.175.00017 (Box 175)
  - Counselors applications, 1951; MS024.002.175.00018 (Box 175)
  - Counselors report, 1946 -- 1961; MS024.002.175.00019 (Box 175)
  - Entr'aide Francaise, 1946; MS024.002.175.00020 (Box 175)
  - Junior counselors, 1950; MS024.002.175.00021 (Box 175)
  - Loose letters, 1961; MS024.002.175.00022 (Box 175)
  - Letters 1946 de France, MS024.002.175.00023 (Box 175)
  - Moniteurs acceptes, 1959; MS024.002.175.00024 (Box 175)
  - Parents of children, Boursiers, 1947; MS024.002.175.00025 (Box 175)
  - Parents of children, Boursiers, 1947; MS024.002.175.00026 (Box 175)
  - Publicity, 1939; MS024.002.175.00027 (Box 175)
  - Registrations, 1951; MS024.002.175.00028 (Box 175)
  - 50th reunion, 1996; MS024.002.176.00001 (Box 176)
  - Applicants, 1963; MS024.002.176.00002 (Box 176)
  - Applicants, 1963; MS024.002.176.00003 (Box 176)
  - Applications - Counselor positions, 1953; MS024.002.176.00004 (Box 176)
  - Applications - Counselors positions, 1953; MS024.002.176.00005 (Box 176)
  - Bossert, 1946 -- 1953; MS024.002.176.00006 (Box 176)
  - Bossert, 1946 -- 1953; MS024.002.176.00007 (Box 176)
  - Camp newsletters, 1932 -- 1956; MS024.002.176.00008 (Box 176)
  - Camp newsletters, 1932 -- 1957; MS024.002.176.00009 (Box 176)
    1932, 1934, 1936, 1937, 1957
  - Camp postwar, 1946 -- 1950; MS024.002.176.00010 (Box 176)
  - Campers, 1963; MS024.002.176.00011 (Box 176)
  - Campers, 1963; MS024.002.176.00012 (Box 176)
  - Chalet camp chatterer, 1937; MS024.002.176.00013 (Box 176)
  - Chalet chatterer, 1938; MS024.002.176.00014 (Box 176)
  - Chalet chatterer, 1939; MS024.002.176.00015 (Box 176)
  - Correspondence copies, 1938; MS024.002.176.00016 (Box 176)
  - Correspondence copies, 1938; MS024.002.176.00017 (Box 176)
  - Correspondence copies, 1938; MS024.002.176.00018 (Box 176)
  - Counselors, 1963; MS024.002.176.00019 (Box 176)
  - Counselors applications, 1955; MS024.002.176.00020 (Box 176)
  - Counselors applications, 1955; MS024.002.176.00021 (Box 176)
  - Letters from teachers, counselors, 1980 -- 1985; MS024.002.176.00022 (Box 176)
  - Letters from counselors/teachers, 1970 -- 1980; MS024.002.176.00023 (Box 176)
  - Loose correspondence, 1935 -- 1955; MS024.002.176.00024 (Box 176)
  - Loose letters, 1927 -- 1963; MS024.002.176.00025 (Box 176)
  - Schedules, individual counselors, 1937; MS024.002.176.00026 (Box 176)
  - Tent town tattler, 1936; MS024.002.176.00027 (Box 176)
  - Applicants, 1947; MS024.002.177.00001 (Box 177)
  - Camp, 1947 -- 1948; MS024.002.177.00002 (Box 177)
  - Camp brochures, 1924 -- 1950; MS024.002.177.00003 (Box 177)
  - Camp, newsclippings, 1947; MS024.002.177.00004 (Box 177)
  - Camp newsletters, 1928 -- 1950; MS024.002.177.00005 (Box 177)
  - Camp, list, supplies, MacJannet committee, 1946; MS024.002.177.00006 (Box 177)
  - Camp organization, 1953; MS024.002.177.00007 (Box 177)
  - Camp organization, 1953; MS024.002.177.00008 (Box 177)
  - Campers, 1947; MS024.002.177.00009 (Box 177)
  - Campers, 1951; MS024.002.177.00010 (Box 177)
  - Campers, 1951; MS024.002.177.00011 (Box 177)
  - Campers, A-C, 1952; MS024.002.177.00012 (Box 177)
  - Campers, D-K, 1952; MS024.002.177.00013 (Box 177)
  - Campers, M-Z, 1952; MS024.002.177.00014 (Box 177)
  - Campers, A-C, 1953; MS024.002.177.00015 (Box 177)
  - Campers, D-I, 1953; MS024.002.177.00016 (Box 177)
  - Campers, J-R, 1953; MS024.002.177.00017 (Box 177)
  - Campers, R-Z, 1953; MS024.002.177.00018 (Box 177)
  - Campers, orphan lists, letters of appreciation, 1948; MS024.002.177.00019 (Box 177)
  - Campers, orphan lists, letters of appreciation, 1948; MS024.002.177.00020 (Box 177)
  - Counselors, 1948; MS024.002.177.00021 (Box 177)
  - Counselors and campers refused, 1938; MS024.002.177.00022 (Box 177)
  - Former counselors, 1946 -- 1960; MS024.002.177.00023 (Box 177)
  - French letters of appreciation, 1949; MS024.002.177.00024 (Box 177)
  - Letters from French campers, 1946; MS024.002.177.00025 (Box 177)
  - Loose letters, 1938; MS024.002.177.00026 (Box 177)
  - Loose letters, 1950; MS024.002.177.00027 (Box 177)
  - Staff material, 1946 -- 1948; MS024.002.177.00028 (Box 177)
  - Camp lists, 1932 -- 1964; MS024.002.177.00029 (Box 177)
  - Camp lists, 1932 -- 1963; MS024.002.177.00030 (Box 177)
  - Journal des operations diverses, 1937 -- 1938; MS024.002.202 (Box 202)
  - Petty cash and payment by check, 1938; MS024.002.204.00001 (Box 204)
  - Salaries: teachers, counselors, secretaries, servants, 1937; MS024.002.204.00002 (Box 204)
  - Ledger, 1936; MS024.002.204.00003 (Box 204)
  - Camp registration/application cards, 1935 -- 1939; MS024.002.237 (Box 237)
- Schools, records and correspondence, 1925 -- 1986; 1925 -- 1938; MS024.003; 2.0 Linear Feet
  This series contains the records and correspondence for the various schools founded by Donald MacJannet. This includes the Elms School in St. Cloud, France, the Trocadero School in Paris, France, the MacJannet Riviera school in Cannes, France and the school in Sun Valley, Idaho. Includes some of the materials relating to Prince Phillip, Duke of Edinburgh, who attended the school as a young boy. This series is rather sparse due to the fact that many of the school records were destroyed by MacJannet himself at the onset of World War II. Elms School report cards also include some faculty information.
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Ledgers, MacJannet school - class, 1937 -- 1938; MS024.003.203 (Box 203)
  - Salaries, 1938 -- 1939; MS024.003.205.00001 (Box 205)
  - Receipts, 1936; MS024.003.205.00002 (Box 205)
  - Petty cash, Payment by checks, Societe generale, dollar account, 1939; MS024.003.205.00003 (Box 205)
  - School accounts, 1938; MS024.003.205.00004 (Box 205)
  - Children teachers, 1936 -- 1937; MS024.003.205.00005 (Box 205)
  - School, 1936; MS024.003.212.00001 (Box 212)
  - MacJannet junior school, 1929 -- 1986; MS024.003.212.00002 (Box 212)
  - Callahan, student files, 1929; MS024.003.217.00001 (Box 217)
  - Correspondence, Brunet, 1938; MS024.003.217.00002 (Box 217)
  - Documents on reclamation of St. Cloud goods, 1939 -- 1946; MS024.003.217.00003 (Box 217)
  - James, student files, 1929; MS024.003.217.00004 (Box 217)
  - Koo, Wellington and Freedman - student files, 1929; MS024.003.217.00005 (Box 217)
  - Letters to J. Dowd, 1930; MS024.003.217.00006 (Box 217)
  - Loose letters re: school and students, 1933; MS024.003.217.00007 (Box 217)
  - MacJannet schools brochures, forms and cards, 1925 -- 1939; MS024.003.217.00008 (Box 217)
  - Paine - student files, 1929; MS024.003.217.00009 (Box 217)
  - Purchase of land at Talloires, 1937; MS024.003.217.00010 (Box 217)
  - School events materials, 1936 -- 1939; MS024.003.217.00011 (Box 217)
  - Student lists, 1939; MS024.003.217.00012 (Box 217)
  - Sun-Fo, Pearl and Rose - student files, 1929; MS024.003.217.00013 (Box 217)
  - Sun valley school, 1940 -- 1945; MS024.003.217.00014 (Box 217)
  - Trocadero scrapbook, 1932; MS024.003.217.00015 (Box 217)
  - Trocadero school scrapbook, 1934; MS024.003.217.00016 (Box 217)
  - Pupil lists, 1929 -- 1936; MS024.003.217.00017 (Box 217)
  - School grades, 1938 -- 1939; MS024.003.217.00018 (Box 217)
  - Day, John - student files, 1929; MS024.003.218.00001 (Box 218)
  - Elms school, 1925 -- 1938; MS024.003.218.00002 (Box 218)
  - Getman, William Fonda, Edward - student files, 1929; MS024.003.218.00003 (Box 218)
  - Indemnity for pillage, letters, 1945 -- 1955; MS024.003.218.00004 (Box 218)
  - 'Leaves from the Elms', 1928 -- 1936; MS024.003.218.00005 (Box 218)
  - Patrick, student files, 1929; MS024.003.218.00006 (Box 218)
  - du Pasquier, student files, 1929 -- 1930; MS024.003.218.00007 (Box 218)
  - School financials, 1938; MS024.003.218.00008 (Box 218)
  - St. Cloud Emory's death, 1938 -- 1939; MS024.003.218.00009 (Box 218)
  - Elms School report cards, 1927 -- 1939; MS024.003.224 (Box 224)
    75 years from the date of creation.
- MacJannet Foundation, 1946 -- 1998; 1966 -- 1999; MS024.004; 2.7 Linear Feet
  This series contains records and correspondence about and with members of the MacJannet Foundation from 1966 to 1999. Includes information about the start of the foundation, as well as those who have benefited from it.
  These materials were collected by Donald and Charlotte MacJannet during the course of their association with the MacJannet Foundation, they are not the archival records of the Foundation itself.
  This series is arranged chronologically within record type.
  - Agenda, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00001 (Box 157)
  - By-laws, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00002 (Box 157)
  - Minutes, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00003 (Box 157)
  - Finances, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00004 (Box 157)
  - B.R. Report, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00005 (Box 157)
  - Brochure, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00006 (Box 157)
  - Correspondence, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00007 (Box 157)
  - Expenses, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00008 (Box 157)
  - Minutes, 1970 -- 1971; MS024.004.157.00009 (Box 157)